Guide to the John Nicholas Beffel Papers TAM.055
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
John Nicholas Beffel Papers
1909-1970
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Beffel, John Nicholas
Beffel, J. Ray
Travaglio, Esther Hartz
Garst, Rina
TAM.055
16.5 Linear Feet 33 boxes, 2 oversize folders
John Nicholas Beffel (1887 1973) was a radical journalist, publicist, and editor. A prolific writer of articles, essays, and publicity dealing with leftist issues, many pertained to the syndicalist labor organization the Industrial Workers of the World (IWW), anarchism and several noted anarchists (he edited several works by or about them). Beffel also produced short stories, autobiographical sketches and poems. Much of his activity involved defense committees for radicals either prosecuted either for their beliefs or for activity related thereto. The collection contains correspondence, subject files, writings by Beffel and others, (unprocessed) Family Files, and an unprocessed Addundum.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Arrangement
The papers are arranged in eight series: I. Correspondence; II. Subject Files; III. Writings by Beffel; IV, Writings by Others; V. Family Files (unprocessed); Series VI: User photocopies from Series IV (Writings by Others); Series VII, Addendum (unprocessed); "Series" VIII: Index to Correspondents. Folder level control for series I, Correspondence; box level control for the remaining series.
Historical/Biographical Note
John Nicholas Beffel (1887 1973) Radical journalist, publicist, and editor. A prolific writer of articles, essays, and publicity dealing with leftist issues, many pertaining to the syndicalist labor organization the Industrial Workers of the World (IWW), anarchism and several noted anarchists. Beffel also produced short stories, autobiographical sketches and poems. Much of his activity involved defense committees for accused radicals in such cases as: the Mooney Billings Case in which the two men were found guilty of a fatal bombing during a Preparedness Day parade in San Francisco in 1916; the Centralia, Washington, case in which ten IWW's were accused of murder during an assault of IWW headquarters in connection with an Armistice Day parade in 1919; Sacco and Vanzetti; the Kentucky Miners Defense, stemming from the bloody "Battle of Evarts" in Harlan County, 1931; the case of Athos Terzani, an anti fascist accused of accidentally murdering a comrade during a fascist rally in New York in 1933; and the un¬solved political murder of anti fascist leader Carlo Tresca in 1943. Beffel was also involved with The League for Mutual Aid, a social service agency for leftists in need of assistance, founded by Roger Baldwin in 1920. Much of the boxes of correspondence relates to Beffel's organizational and publicity efforts in these causes; much of the rest concerns his writings or those of his correspondents. Beffel edited several (published and unpblished) manuscripts, primarily by or about various anarchists (including Mikhail Bakunin, Rose Pesotta, and Harry Kelley, co-founder of the Ferrer colony in Stelton, N.J.), was interested in, and wrote about mysterious disappearances, and sometimes wrote articles under the names of Lancey Fitzgibbons, George Moresby, Mary Starland, Daniel Tower and others.
Scope and Contents
The papers contain correspondence, subject fifles, writings (by Beffel and others), Family files (unprocessed), an Index to Series I, Correspondence, and an unprocessed Addendum. Correspondents include Richard Brazier, Ralph Chaplin, Daniel Eisenberg, Aldino Felicani, Covington Hall, Harvey O'Connor, Rose Pesotta, Anna Roy, Vincent Starrett, Fred Thompson, Wilma Haywood Veleker, Albert Wehde, Art Young, and numerous family members. Note that correspondence is also found throughout the subject files. Series II, Subject Files, chiefly relate to Beffel's organizational and publicity efforts in the defense of accused radicals in the Mooney-Billings case, Centralia, Wash.; a case involving members of the Industrial Workers of the World (WW); the Sacco-Vanzetti case; the Kentucky miners' defense in Harlan County (1931); the case of Athos Terzani; and Beffel's involvement with the League for Mutual Aid, a social service agency for leftists. The two Writings series contain manuscripts of writings by Beffel and others, including Bakunin's Political Philosophy: His Writings on Scientific Anarchism, edited by Beffel; several chapters from Rose Pesotta's Bread Upon the Waters (1944), edited by Beffel and Days of Our Lives (1958), both before editorial changes; unpublished autobiographies by Harry Kelly (co-founder of the Ferrer colony in Stelton, N.J.)and Enness Ellae (IWW member); published and unpublished articles and essays, most about labor and leftist personalities and issues; and stories, poems, reviews, and autobiographical pieces on Beffel's boyhood in Seneca, Ill. and notes for a book. Although preoccupied with leftist causes, Beffel manifested a deep interest in his writings in mysterious disappearances; notes for a book on the subject is found here under the title "Where Did These Men Die?"
NOTE: There is an Index to Correspondents ("Series" VIII) at the end of the container list. This Index references correspondents represented in more than one location in the collection, and in particular, correspondents represented in Series II, Subjects. Conversely,the SEE and SEE ALSO references found in Series II, Subjects, refer researchers to additional correspondence by the individuals in question to be found in Series I, Correspondence, for which there is a folder level container list.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by J. Ray Beffel (brother of John Nicholas Beffel) via Robert Calese in 1973. An additional accession was donated by Esther Hartz Travaglio via Paul Avrich in 1974, and another accession was donated by Rina Garst in 1991. The accession numbers associated with these gifts are 1972.001, 2018.002, NPA 1993.016, and NPA 2005.070.
Custodial History
Robert Calese, friend of John Nicholas Beffel, delievered Beffel's papers to Tamiment Library after Beffel's death in 1973. Shortly after, J. Ray Beffel, brother of John Nicholas Beffel, granted Tamiment Library permission to keep the materials delivered by Calese.
Esther Hartz Travaglio's donated materials in 1994. These materials were delivered to Tamiment Library by Paul Avrich.
Rina Garst, niece of Lisa Luchkovsky (Beffel estate trustee), donated materials in 1991.
Manuscripts; Reviews (document genre); Evarts (Ky.); Sacco-Vanzetti Trial, Dedham, Mass., 1921.; Stelton (N.J.); Harlan County (Ky.); Anarchists.; Autobiographies.; Syndicalists |z United States.; Syndicalism |z United States.; Right and left (Political science).; Anarchists -- Biography.; Beffel, John Nicholas; Fitzgibbons, Lancey; Gandhi, Mahatma, 1869-1948; Feliciani, Aldino, 1891-1967; Mooney, Thomas J., 1882-1942; Moresby, George; Hall, Covington, 1871-1951; Kelly, Harry; Rocker, Rudolf, 1873-1958.; Roy, Anna; O'Connor, Harvey, 1897-1987.; Pesotta, Rose, 1896-; Kentucky Miners Defense; League for Mutual Aid (U.S.); Modern School (Stelton, N.J.); Chaplin, Ralph, 1887-1961; Eisenberg, Daniel; Ellae, Enness; Industrial Workers of the World; Baldwin, Roger Nash, 1884-1981; Billings, Warren K., 1893-1972; Bluestein, Abe; Thompson, Fred, 1900-1987; Tresca, Carlo, 1879-1943.; Terzani, Athos; Starrett, Mary; Starrett, Vincent, 1886-1974; Wehde, Albert; Young, Art, 1866-1943.; Beffel, J. Ray; Travaglio, Esther Hartz; Garst, Rina
- Series I: Correspondence, 238842; 0 Linear Feet
  Scope and Content Note
  John Nicholas Beffel corresponded with over five hundred individuals. In addition to the names included in the folder titles below, the following indivudals are represented in this series:
  Dr. Frank Abbate, Herman Abramson, Farrar Andre Addie, Mary Ahlquist, Ruth Albert, Dr. Carmen Aldecoa, L. E. Aller, Vincenzo Alvano, Louise Andrews, Ernest Angell, Armand Aulicino, A. M. Aurand (Jr.), Sally Axelrod, Forrest Bailey, Angelica Balabanoff, Roger Baldwin, S. J. Ballard, Mrs. Eugene Barnett, Dick Barry, Dr. Elizabeth Bass, Lydia M. Baxter, Helen Marston Beardsley, John Beardsley, Ray Becker, Daniel Bell, Hillaire Belloc, Isadora Bennet, Hella Bernays, Sister Mary Bertille, F. R. Better, Mrs. Blankenehorn, Frank Bohn, Frank Branch, Beltrando And Muriel Brini, Elizabeth J. Brooks, Haywood Broun, F. A. Brown, Jane Browne, Louis Budnez, Dr. Ralph J. Bunche, Evelyn Burke, Thomas Burke, Richard A. Bury, Samuel Byer, Edmund Cahn, Robert Calese, Bruce Calvert, Beatrice Canzanelli, Jack Carel, Hon. Alexander J. Cella, Hon. A. B. Chandler, Mr. Churchill, Louis Ciccone, Bennett Champ Clark, Clara Clayman, Travers Clement, Marye S. Clinton, Joe Coldwell, Mcalister Coleman, Arthur Coleman?, Ruth Collat, Phyllis Collier, Lillian Collins, Margaret Colson, Hon. Calvin Coolidge, Frank B. Coon, James P. Cooney, Sal Coppola, Minnie Federman Corder, E. J. Costello, George Cowley, Kate Crane Gartz, Louise Crimmins, Donald M. Crocker, Robert Cromie, Frank R. Crosswaith, Paul And Tanya Crouch, Homer Croy, May Savell Croy, Cyrus H. K. Curtis, Tom Daly, Leigh Dannenberg, H. M. Davidson, Rachel Davis Dubois, Robert H. Davis, F. Trubee Davison, Dorothy Day, Theodore Debs, Norman Thomas De Giovanni, Solon De Leon, Margaret De Silver, Ann Folder Decker, Leah C. Degnan, Floyd Dell, Joe Dermondy, Babette Deutsch, William T. Dewart, Roberta (Mrs. John) Dewey, Mario Di Marco, Z. N. Diamond, Lillian Kisluik Dinowitzer, Ellen Donahue, Mary (Hapgood) Donovan, John Dos Passos, Mary Dougherty, Hon. William 0. Douglas, Thomas Dreier, Robert W. Dunn, Tamara. Dwir, Ralph M. Easley, Walter P. Eaton, Justus Ebert, Herbert B. Ehrman, Robert B. Eleazer, Morris L. Ellis, Helen Warder? Erskine, Ernestine Evans, J. L. T. Evans, Robert Evett, O. G Fairburn, James Farmer, Harry Feinberg, Mrs. John Fellows, Fred S. Ferguson, Lawrence Fernworth, Sara Field, Elizabeth Gurley Flynn, Kathryn Flynn, Richard Ford, Osmond K. Fraenkel, Jack Frager, Adelaide Shulkind Frank, Nelson Frank, Walter Frank, Bessie Freiberg, Louise Friese, Henry B. Fuller, Maude Fulton, John A. Gahan, Mary E. Gallagher, Mahatma Gandhi, D. Gardiner, Hy Gardner, Frances Gates, Robert Gavin, Gladys Bell Gehrig, Dorothea And Leon Gelber, Harrison George, Rodman Gilder, Elizabeth Gilman, Ny Glickstein, Ed Goete?, Emma Goldman, Ferd Gottlieb, B. A. Green, Elizabeth Griffin, Phillys B. Grosser, Louis Grudin, Martha Gruening, Eula Guy, Walter F. Haas, Carl Haessler, Rosa Laddon Hanna, Harry Hansen, Virginia Mishnun Hardman, Donald Harrington, Michael Harrington, Frank Harris, Nora Havel, Carter H. Hawkins, Arthur Garfield Hayes, William B. Haywood, Dr. William Hazlett, Dennis Heaton (Jr.), Ammon Hennacy, Sidney Hertzberg, E. W. Heubsch, Joe Hill, Walter Hill, Joseph Hillstrom, Katherine H. Hodgins, Hon. Frank S. Hogan, Calm Morrison Hoke, Tom Holland, Dr. Maurice L. Hollod, Mary Hope, Arthur Hopkins, Lena Horne, Michael Howie, Marian? Humble, Catherine Huntington, Valerio Isca, Gardiner Jack, Agnes Jarrett, Oakley Johnson, Tom Johnston, Joseph Emmett Jones, G. Louis Joughin, Helen Joyce, Milton Kahn, Isadore Katz, Nicholas De B. Katzenibach, Helen Keller, Rosemary Kelley, Emmett J. Kelly, Harry Kelly, Ellen A. Kennan, Hon. Dorothy Kenyon, Alice Mary Kimball, James King, George W. Kirchway, Henry Klinger, Cornelius Knutson, Nathan Korby, Teng Kwei, Bill Laidlaw, Ben Hur Lampman, C. S. Lane, E. W. Latchem, Miss. Lathrop, Rev. Charles N. Lathrop, Ray Lattimer, Agnes C. Laut, Hesper Le Gallienne, Fred Learned, Deryl Leggit, Max Lehman, John Lester, Jeanne Levey, David Levinson, George Lewis, Marx Lewis, Sinclair Lewis, William Wallace Liggett, Harry Lindholm, Walter Lippmann, Louis P. Lochner, Jack London, Frank R. Lopez, David Loth, Rev. Donald G. Lothrop, Robert M. Lovett, H. Burton Lowe, Ester Lowell, Robert Lowell, John M. Lundoff, Mrs. A. Lunldelius, R. H. Lyman, Eugene Lyons, Louis Lyons, Nat Marer, A. J. Marks, Frank X. Martel, Alberto Martin, Anna Martin, Pete Martin, Mrs. Lee Matteson, Ben A. Matthews, C. Egan Mauchenheim, Meyer Emil Maurer, Diana Truesdale May, Allen Maynard, Louis R. Maynard, Fred J. Mc Arthur, Msgr. Joseph J. McCaffrey, Lucy Mcdonald, William Mcfee, Andrew Mcgill, John Mcgivney, Hon. James Mcgurrin, Charles Mcknight, Alex Mclean, Hon. Edmund L. McNamara, Dr. Kate Campbell Hurd Mead, Anna Meagan, Beatrice Meitlein, Rose Meitlein, Joseph Meltzer, Sam Merling, Jean Duval Michener, Morris Milgram, Mrs. John E. Milholland, G. E. Miller, Pauline Millet, Carl G. Milligan, A. Mingana, Robert Minor, Jaume Miravitelles, Gordon Mitchell, Zapata Modesto, Alexander J. Moffat, E. Howard Molisani, Francis X. Moloney, (Peo) Monoldi, Vanni Montana, Tom Mooney, Fred H. Moore, Lola D. Moore, Rob Moore, U. G. Moore, T. J. Moran, D. F. Morehouse, T. S. Morgan, Christopher Morley, Guilio De Moro, Mr. W.F. Moudy, Pauli Murray, Hon. Michael A. Musmanno, Marshall Naely, Scott Nearing, Fanny Neff, Louis Nelson, Walter M. Nelson, Dr. John H. Nichols, Jens Nielsen, Robert M. Noah, P. J. Nolan, Miss Agnes F. Northrop, Rose Norwood, Jessie Oakley, Fremont Oder, Tom C. O'Donnel, Frank P O'Hare, Eugene O'Neill, Jessie Orcutt, Alexis Oscar Outtier, Adele Parker Burnett, Miss Parkhurst, Mr. Phillips, Herbert Pick Man, Vivian Pierce, Dr. Pitman, Ernest Poole, Adna Porter, Roscoe Pound, Mr. Pringle, G. D. Procopio, Dorothy Purdell, Jim Putnam, S. V. Quam, Luigi Quintiliano, Dachine Rainer, A. Philip Randolpti, Miss Ransdell, John Regan, Frieda Reichner, Dr. Herbert Reinemann, Ed Reid, Mary E. Richmond, Sue J. Robertson, Louise Rogers, Jack Rohan, Dick Rohman, Jack Rudome, Paul Rugen, Charles Edward Russell, Isaac K. Russell, William F. Ryan, Howard Samuel, Hon. Thomas D. Schall, Otto J. Schneider, Marjorie Schoultz, Lawrence Seco, Nina Seco, George Seldes, Thomas Seltzer, Morris Shapiro, Judge Ben Sheeks, John Shuskie, S. Fanny Simon, Smith C. S., Britt Smith, Elmer S. Smith, Harry Smith, Katherine Smith, Edgar C. Snyder, Helen Sobell, Marshall Solberg, Sidney Solomon, Sigmund Spaeth, Michael Spano, Rose Spitzner, Louis Stark, Ellen Gates Starr, Frederick Starr, Walter Starrett, Molly Steimer, Sophia Steinbach, Isabel Stephan, Irving Stone, Sydney Strong, Louis Stulberg, Herman Suhr, Leslie B. Sulgrove, Adelaide Sulkind, Frank Sullivan, Timothy Sullivan, George W. Sutton (Jr.), Dorothy Swanson, Coleman C. Sweet, Lillian Symies, D. L. Taleath, John Tatty, Sara (Filsinger) Teasdale, Athos Terzani, Dr. Evan Thomas, R.C. Thompson, Mrs. E. S. L. Thompson, William G. Thompson, Worth M. Tippy, C. C. Tisler, Howard Tompkins, Marie Torre, Alexander Trachtenberg, Ann And Horace Traubel, Beatrice Tresca, Peg Tucker, John I. Turner, Miss Turner, Gertrude Tyler, Gus Tyler, Walter Ufers, Girolamo Valenti, Sylvia Miller Valenti, George F. Vandeveer, Oswald Garrison Villard, Robert F. Wagner, Stanley Walker, M. J. Walsh, Doris Wan Nierstrom, James Warbasse, Ann Watkins, Rowland Watts, David Weinstein, Harris Weinstock, P. J. Welinder, P. H. Whaley, Grant White, Jack White, Belle Fligleman Winestine, Kathryn Wolf, Bertram D. Wolfe, Louis Wolheim, Charles W. Wood, Leone Wood, Frederick A. Woodward, Palmer Wright, B. (Boris ?) Yelensky, A. Cameron Young, Modesto Zapata, and Charles Zerner.
  - A, 1910-1960; 244859 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Appel, Paul, 1924-1969, undated; 244860 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - B, 1921-1968, undated; 244861 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Brazier, Richard, 1924-1968, undated; 244862 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Buckley, John, 1968-1969; 244863 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Burr, Jane, 1918-1957, undated; 244864 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - C, 1911-1970; 244865 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Campbell, Agnes H. (includes photograph), undated; 244866 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Campbell, Agnes H., undated; 244867 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Campbell, Agnes H., 1922; 244868 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Campbell, Agnes H., 1923; 244869 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Campbell, Agnes H., 1923; 244870 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Campbell, Agnes H., 1924; 244871 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Campbell, Agnes H., 1924; 244872 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Campbell, Agnes H., 1924; 244873 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Campbell, Agnes H., 1925; 244874 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Campbell, Agnes H. (includes photographs), 1925; 244875 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Campbell, Agnes H., 1926; 244876 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Campbell, Agnes H., 1927; 244877 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Campbell, Agnes H., 1928; 244878 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Campbell, Agnes H., 1929; 244879 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Campbell, Agnes H., 1930; 244880 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Campbell, Agnes H., 1931; 244881 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Campbell, Agnes H., 1932, 1937-1938; 244882 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Campbell, Agnes H. (from Various People), 1924-1925; 244883 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Carey, Eugene F., 1947, undated; 244884 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Cascaden, Gordon, 1935-1936, undated; 244885 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Chamberlain, Grace Ann, undated; 244886 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Carson, Saul and Betty, 1937-1966, undated; 244887 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Chamberlain, Grace Anne (includes photograph), 1920-1921; 244888 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Chamberlain, Grace Anne, 1940; 244889 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Chamberlain, Grace Anne, 1940-1960; 244890 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Chamberlain, Grace Anne: Various Book Chapters and REsearch Clippings for Unpublished Book "When You Visit the Sick", 1937-1940; 244891 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Chaplin, Ralph, 1923-1937, undated; 244892 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Clinton, Sackville H.M., 1937-1967, undated; 244893 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Clinton, Sackville H.M., 1962-1965; 244894 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Clinton, Sackville H.M., 1966; 244895 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Clinton, Sackville H.M., 1967; 245014 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Clinton, Sackville H.M., 1968; 245015 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Clinton, Sackville H.M., 1969-1970; 245016 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Comfort, Will Levington, 1910-1912, undated; 245017 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - D, 1910-1970; 245018 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Davin, Tom, 1937-1941; 245019 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Diggins, John P., 1965-1966; 245020 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Dillion, Mary, 1914-1920, undated; 245021 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Dreiser, Theodore, 1914-1932; 245022 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - E, 1924-1969, undated; 245023 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Eisenberg, Daniel, 1938-1961, undated; 245024 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Eisenberg, Daniel (with Farrar and Rinehart Publishers, 1938-1944; 245025 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Eisenberg, Daniel (Memorandums, etc. by JNB: RE: I Find the Missing), 1938, undated; 245026 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Eisenberg, Daniel (Beffel Correspondence RE: I Find the Missing), 1937-1938; 245027 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Eisenberg, Daniel (Miscellaneous Publicity and Reviews, Etc.), 1938, undated; 245028 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - F, 1918-1966, undated; 245029 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Felicani, Aldino and Ateo, 1947-1970, undated; 245030 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Fletcher, Ben, 1967-1969; 245031 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Fresco, Mauricio, 1937; 245032 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Fuessle, Helen, 1925-1926; 245033 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Fuller, Torrey, 1932-1961, undated; 245034 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Furman, Lee, 1937-1941; 245035 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - G, 1919-1966, undated; 245036 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Gawthorpe, Mary (Sanders), 1938-1964; 245037 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Gehrig, Gladys Bell (includes photographs), 1925-1929, undated; 245038 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - H (includes photograph), 1912-1970, undated; 245039 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - H (Hodgins?), K., 1924-1940; 245040 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Hall, Covington, 1937-1950; 245041 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Hapgood, Mary Donovan, 1964-1969; 245042 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Hilson, Maxine, 1934-1940; 245043 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Humphrey, Mary, 1925-1938, undated; 245044 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - I, 1967; 245045 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Inalis, Agnes, 1936-1967; 245046 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - J, 1919-1968, undated; 245047 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Jarrett, Ida, 1965-1968; 245048 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - K, 1923-1966; 245049 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Karsner, David, 1918-1932, undated; 245050 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Karsten, Helen Ward Tippy, 1921-1967, undated; 245051 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Keller, Carl, 1925-1969; 245052 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Kenderdine, John D., 1925-1966, undated; 245053 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Kitchen, Irene, 1960-1969; 245054 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - L, 1911-1967, undated; 245055 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Lonergan, Hella and Warren, 1933-1968; 245056 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Luchkovsky, Lisa, 1959; 245057 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Luchkovsky, Lisa, 1960-1967; 245058 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Lyla, 1938-1942; 245059 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - M, 1909-1969, undated; 245060 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Mahler, Herbert, 1937-1961; 245061 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - McSwigan, Marie, 1935-1940; 245062 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Mencken, H.L., 1914-1938; 245063 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous, 1911-1966, undated; 245064 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - RE: Mooney, Tom, 1920-1931; 245065 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - N, 1934-1969; 245066 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Naretty, Vera, 1938-1966; 245067 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Nomad, Max, 1968; 245068 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - O, 1916-1966, undated; 245069 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - O'Connor, Harvey, 1926-1969; 245070 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - O'Connor, Tom, 1939; 245071 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - O'Connor, Tom, 1960-1961; 245072 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - O'Conner, Tom, 1961-1966; 245073 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - P, 1930-1951; 245074 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Pesotta, Rose, 1949-1965; 245075 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Pesotta, Rose: "Bread Upon the Waters" Book Manuscript (Different from the Published Book), undated; 245076 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Pesotta, Rose (Typescript "Days of Our Lives" Probably Chpater 12 of Sweetheart of the Army), 1952; 245077 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Price, Burr, 1910-1940; 245078 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Q, 1934; 245079 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - R, 1913-1966; 245080 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Roy, Anna (Includes Manuscript for Unpublished Book Chapter), 1969; 245081 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - S, 1907-1969, undated; 245082 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - S, Laura, 1941; 245083 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Sandberg, Carl, 1920-1966; 245084 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Sheehan, Lucy and Bill, 1925-1939; 245085 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Shields, Art and Ester, 1920-1969; 245086 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Schulkind, Adelaide, 1930-1970; 245087 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Sinclair, Upton, 1920-1967; 245088 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Spivak, John L. (AKA Jack), 1965-1968; 245089 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Scarlett, Vincent, 1918-1967; 245090 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - T, 1910-1967; 245091 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Teichner, Miriam, 1914-1928; 245092 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Thomas, Norman, 1936-1968; 245093 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Thompson, Fred (RE: Joe Hill), 1947-1967; 245094 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Travaglio, Esther Hartz, 1926-1970; 245095 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Tresca, Carlo, 1944-1969; 245096 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Trunck, Irene, 1939-1949; 245097 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - U, 1928; 245098 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - V, 1919; 245099 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - RE: Valenti, Girolamo (Obituary), 1966-1967; 245100 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Veleker, Wilma Haywood, 1962-1968; 245101 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - W, 1910-1969; 245102 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - W, Margaret, 1936-1952; 245103 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Walling, Anna Struncky, 1916-1970; 245104 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Wehde, Albert, 1923-1926; 245105 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Wehde, Albert, 1927-1941; 245106 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Wehde, Albert (Wehde Letters with Others than Beffel), 1923-1931, undated; 245107 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Wehde, Albert: RE: Book Fingerprints Can Be Forged (Includes Manuscript Drafts and Reviews), 1925-1938; 245108 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Wehde, Albert: RE: Book Fingerprints Can Be Forged (Promotional Materials from Tremonia Publishing Co.), 1923-1926, undated; 245109 (Box 9, Folder 1)